Corey L. Slade

San Diego, CA • (760) 822-2474 • corey.slade@gmail.com

• https://github.com/Throwback74 • https://www.linkedin.com/in/corey-slade/ • https://www.linkedin.com/in/corey-slade/ • www.coreyslade.com/in/corey-slade/ • www.coreyslade.com/in/corey-slade/ • https://www.linkedin.com/in/corey-slade/ • <a href="https://w

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer from San Diego with a life-long dedication to learning and his sights set on a full-time web development position. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Adept at building a sophisticated website with full database back end all the way from mock-up to roll-out as well as working with diverse teams to implement projects. Past experience in the Pharmaceutical industry as well as Political Consulting and nearly a decade of customer service and leadership roles

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Experienced with both front-end and back-end development in the MERN stack. Skilled in the use of HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, TypeScript, Node.js, Express, Firebase, MySQL, Sequelize.js, Handlebars, MongoDB, Mongoose, Nano-SQL and React. As well as Front-end Frameworks such as Bootstrap, Materialize, Bulma.io, Office UI Fabric React, and Material Design/Material Design Lite.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Independent Contractor

October 2018 – Current

Full Stack Web Developer

Full Stack development in the MERN Stack to provide bug fixes, new features, updates to existing features, and assist in creating a new projects from the ground up.

Some representative past and present clients include: Adigami, BudBytes

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Journey On MERN Stack App

Built with Node, Express, Mongo/Mongoose, React

- Provided users with advice, resources, Kanban board, Calendar and database for personal inspiration and resources, and taught how to set realistic tasks in an aim to help users achieve their long-term goals.
 - ➤ GitHub https://github.com/Throwback74/Journey_On
 - Deployed https://journeyonandon.herokuapp.com/

Softphone

Full Stack App

Built with Node, Express, MySQL/Sequelize, Passport.js

- A software-based phone app built using the Twilio API allowing the user to make domestic or
 international calls and store their contacts in a personal phonebook. Designed to replace the need for
 phone cards for anyone with internet access by providing cheap or free domestic and international calls.
 - GitHub https://github.com/Throwback74/goSoftPhone
 - Deployed https://gosoftphone.herokuapp.com/

React Memory Game

React Web App

Built with Node, Express, MySQL/Sequelize, Passport.js

- A simple memory game, click the same image more than once and you lose! All 30 images are shuffled using the Fisher-Yates algorithm each click, with 12 of them being displayed at a time.
 - GitHub https://github.com/Throwback74/react-clicky-game
 - Deployed https://react-clickygame-cbc.herokuapp.com/

EXPERIENCE

Covance Inc.

San Diego, CA

Program Specialist (contracted through Corestaff)

October 2017-April 2018

Provided case management services for patients and their providers for multiple Covance programs. Quickly responded to incoming calls and faxes, determined program eligibility, placed follow up calls for missing information, identified and owned issues, navigated insurance programs, and worked to remove obstacles preventing patients or providers from accessing treatment. Recognized for near perfect metrics multiple times, and moved through training stages at an accelerated pace in recognition of performance. Assisted in the training of new team members and created scripts, references, and resources to ease the learning curve of starting a new program. Educated patients on insurance options and the marketplace and assisted in navigating the insurance approval process and Prior Authorizations as well as potentially finding alternative funding when needed.

Corey L. Slade

San Diego, CA • (760) 822-2474 • corey.slade@gmail.com

• https://github.com/Throwback74 • https://www.linkedin.com/in/corey-slade/ • www.coreyslade.com

GreatCall, Inc.

Carlsbad, CA

Customer Service Agent

March 2016-February 2017

Customer Service Agent for GreatCall, a cell phone and safety device provider. Handled a multitude of incoming calls from customers each day, regarding issues ranging from emergencies, to disconnects, troubleshooting, billing questions, rate plan changes, retentions, and more. Handled a high volume of calls every day with the goal of one call resolution for every customer's problem. Also responsible for meeting adherence, revenue, and retention goals and recognized for the highest retention numbers of the team. Created multiple new policies regarding exchanges and returns adopted by corporate and used to significantly increase retention rates company-wide.

Reuters/Ipsos Encinitas, CA

State Director

September 2014-November 2014

National Field Team

Brought on as State Director (SD) of Montana and a member of the National Field Team (NFT) for the Reuters/Ipsos Election Reporting Project (RIERP) in recognition of excellent work during the ESI contract. As SD, prepared for Election night by finalizing the new contact network of election officials building upon previous data. Successfully led a team of 5 Regional Coordinators (RC) and 56 EAs, ensuring proper coverage of all 56 counties and verified all results were reported, later being recognized as one of only a few states to achieve 100% reporting. For the NFT, worked to assist other SDs in their preparation by calling to areas where the Election Agent (EA) had received pushback about RIERP reporting local results. Managed conference calls to answer questions and provide technical assistance to EAs, RCs, and other SDs from across the country.

Election Systems Inc. Carlsbad, CA

Data Coordinator/IT Technician

June 2013-September 2014

Initially worked on the RIERP, made calls and reached out to local election officials across the country, building a contact network from the ground up for the 2014 Election. Other projects included qualifying multiple petitions for the ballot - processed and validated petitions for errors, duplicates, fraud, etc. Primarily built spreadsheets to track the results of processing, consolidated information, coordinated with subcontractors for receiving and follow up, communicated the results and discussed any issues. Promoted and put in charge of in-house IT work, computer and network set up, troubleshooting, and minor server tasks using MySQL.

The Home Depot Encinitas, CA
Head Cashier December 2008 – March 2013

Promoted in less than 6 months and recognized multiple times for excellent customer service. Expedited customers through the store's registers by ensuring efficient operation by the cashier and front-end operations teams. Ensured that there were no lines and that all team members went to breaks and lunches on time, with all customers receiving a fast, friendly, accurate checkout, taking over cashier and lot attendant duties as needed. Assisted in training and supervision of cashiers, teaching proper procedures and Code of Conduct, as well as ensuring monthly training was completed on time and identifying areas for improvement and providing coaching or retraining where needed.

TRAINING and EDUCATION

UC San Diego Extension

San Diego, CA

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

August 2018

A full-time student in the fast-paced full stack flex program covering theory and application of web development. The curriculum covered HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Java, jQuery, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Firebase, Cookies, Local Storage, Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Database Theory, Handlebars, MongoDB, Mongoose, MySQL, Sequelize, Security and Session Storage, User Authentication, Command Line, Git, and more.

Mira Costa College Phi Theta Kappa President's List Encinitas, CA August 2012-December 2016